Hi. Well, it's been 17 over 17 years
I've been in this YouTube game and I
became the first full-time engineering
YouTuber, pioneer this whatever it is we
do. And um about the same date, it was
about April 4th, 2011. So, 2 years later
became full-time at this gig and you've
seen my 100,000 um SUBSCRIBER YOUTUBE
PLAY BUTTON with my Nixie Tube display.
I've done a whole design series on the
Nixie Tube display. Um that yeah, it's
not operational at the moment cuz I
don't know the API broke or something
like that. Um need to fix that. And I've
got my EV Log 2 channel. I got the award
for that. But, of course, I put in bring
back the dislike count, but that is
actually uh the YouTube Silver Award.
So, 17 years later I'm still here, still
doing the same thing.
And it arrived, the YouTube gold play
button. Looks like the same size as the
silver one. I thought it would be
bigger. Um that's what everyone says
when they meet me in real life, by the
way. I thought you'd be bigger, Dave.
No, I'm just average height. And I guess
this is an average gold play button. I
think they used to be really big, right?
The gold uh play button. But, anyway, it
arrived. Woohoo! Start the party. Um
yeah, bit anticlimactic, I got to say
after 17 years cuz my growth has just
been pretty much linear the whole way.
So, it was like it I haven't gone viral,
haven't jumped up and instantly got an
extra couple hundred thousand subs or
something. No, it's just grinding away,
you know, couple of thousand subscribers
a month or something like that is what I
get at the moment. But, thank you every
single person who has subscribed and
watched uh one of my videos. And a lot
and a lot of people have uh you know,
dropped off over the years as you lose
interest in you, grow in your career. A
lot of people say, "Oh, I used to watch
you as a student." And absolutely
fantastic. That's what I'm in this game
for. I love it. So, yeah, genuinely,
thank you, everyone, for the YouTube
Gold Play Button. So, let's open it.
Yes, just like the Bring Back the
Dislike Count, I could have actually put
any name on there I wanted. They
actually let you put anything on there
up to, you know, 100 characters or
something. I did actually put EEVblog
on. So, um
let's get the big knife and let's open
this thing. Yeah.
17 years. You get less for murder. Um
here we go. So,
let's Who is I don't even know who the
CEO of YouTube is these days. Uh uh
Mohan or something? Am I think getting
it wrong? I don't know. Uh Does anyone
care anymore? Um here it is.
You will see it before I see it. Or
maybe
maybe not because it's going to have
some black felt. Here we go. You're
going to see it first.
Oh, hide it. Is it there? There's a
note, right? There's a note. Oh, oh,
it's on thick card. Oh, how does it
look? Is it upside down? No, it's not
upside down. Oh,
look at that.
YouTube.
Turning at the right angle matters. Uh
yeah.
Recognize your team. Oh, yeah, you can
buy more. You can get them for the buy
them extras for like 300 bucks a pop or
something like that. And you can buy
like a little desktop one as well. They
provide a link, but there it is.
Presented to E. Jeez. Presented to
EEVblog for passing 1 million
subscribers. YouTube, it's all
capitalized properly, and it's all
reflective. Look at that.
Isn't that a Bobby Dazzler? There you
go. Compare it to the silver. They've
They've standardized, haven't they?
They're
identical, right?
But gold and silver
identical.
Okay. Yeah, I'm sure I've seen some
YouTube Gold Awards where they're like
enormous things and they barely fit on
the wall or whatever. People are
struggling to find places on the wall,
but
they've standardized on the little one
now.
But, it's gold color, so yeah.
I've actually got gold. I wonder
if I can melt down some gold and
actually have like a real gold
a play thing in there.
I'd have to talk to so I know somebody
who might be able to make that happen.
>> [snorts]
>> Smells like a million subscribers. Um
yeah, there it is. Thank you, everyone.
Oh, go well. Hello, let's read the
thing. Um
you didn't have didn't have these when I
started but I only had these for the
like the the Googles for the last
6 years, seven Is it 6, 7 years now?
But, uh 17 years ago, didn't have the
Googles, didn't have the gray hair
either. Um you did it. One mission, one
channel, and one more thing. 1 million
subscribers. Congratulations. You may
have started with just a few viewers,
but your voice, passion, and creativity
have now touched the lives of people
around the world. That is actually the
best part about this, by the way, is
like people telling me, "Yeah, I watched
you through university. Got me or it got
me inspired to get into electronics."
Hear it all the time and from other
creators as well saying, "Oh, Dave, I
you know, I started watching your
videos, decided to start my own
channel." Absolutely fantastic. It's the
most rewarding part of the business. And
community that you've built is your rich
by the stories that you shared as you
bring people together. Shout out to the
people on the EV blog forum, of course.
Um to honor this milestone, I'm proud to
present you with a gold creator award.
Hope that Hope that this special
recognition will remind you how much you
mean to so many. More.
Every day you are redefining how content
is created and watched, one voice and
one video at a time. That's not AI. Can
you get rid of the AI slop, please? Um
it's a privilege to be You know, on the
one hand,
you want us you know, you're pushing all
these AI tools on us and on the other
hand you go, "Well, we don't want any AI
slop." And it's kind of like, "What the
hell's going on?" It's a privilege to be
part of your journey. We can't wait to
see what you do next. Neal Mohan. Yeah,
I was right, Mohan. Somebody. Thank you
very much, Neal Mohan. I'm sure did not
personally sign that. But anyway, um
there it is. Gold Play Button.
Cool bananas. It's pretty schmick, isn't
it? Um Yeah, might have to hang it on
the wall. I don't know. It's got some
hanger points. Um
yeah, no, I've run out of room on the
shelf. So, yeah, I think I'm going to
have to start whacking them up on the
wall. And I need to uh get this Nixie
tube uh
subscriber counter cuz it would have
been cool to have it tick over. I
actually planned for the millionth um
subscriber tick over, I planned to
actually get this working again. And
uh you know, watch it actually do a live
stream, which I eventually did. But um a
live stream and then watch it tick over
to the million subscribers and that
would have been the official uh thing.
But um
um it just snuck up on me, actually. So,
I didn't get time to do that. But I
didn't actually manage to do a uh live
um an impromptu live show for one 1
millionth subscriber. But there it is.
It eventually turned up. There seems to
be like a hysteresis thing on here. You
don't automatically get the email. As
soon as you pass you know, million
subscribers, don't expect the email to
automatically come into your inbox. It
does actually uh take um time to get it.
I think I was at uh extra 2,000 1,500
subscribers over or something before I
actually got the email that said, "Hey,
you can now order this." So, I must have
a hysteresis there. Just in case you
you get over and then plummet back down
or something, I guess. So, yeah.
Cool bananas, huh? Gold Play Button, 17
years.
It's a bit anticlimactic, [laughter]
I've got to say.
17 years is a long time. There's people
that get a million How many channels are
there? I once did the numbers on it.
There were over 100,000 channels that
had 100,000 subscribers, and that was
like six or seven years ago when I
looked at the numbers. I'd love to know
how many channels actually have a
million
subscribers now. So, if I can find that
info, I'll include it in the overlay
here. But, thank you everyone who has
subscribed. That's pretty awesome. Um
weather, aren't you? Well, yeah, you
have to have you have to be subscribed
to be in this count. Can't just watch my
videos and not be subscribed. So,
million people are subscribed. I know a
lot have dropped off over the years as
interests change. I subscribe to
channels and I religiously watch like
every day and then eventually, you know,
my interests change. It happens.
But, still going strong, still driving
the billy cart. The wheels aren't even
close to falling off the billy cart on
the EV blog yet, but you can bet your
bottom dollar that I'll still be
steering the billy cart when the wheels
totally fall off this thing. So, yeah, I
ain't going nowhere. It's a million
subscribers. I won't get to the 10
million. Pretty much guarantee you that.
Kind of a big deal if a little
anticlimactic after 17 [laughter]
years. But, anyway, I'm in it for the
long game. So, genuine thanks again to
everyone who subscribed and watched and
contributed to the forum and donated and
Patreon supporters. Uh
people who just, you know, send me
PayPal donations and people who just um
send stuff into the mailbag and all
sorts of things and the manufacturers
and
uh you know, the advertisers on the
forum. Everyone who has supported me and
kept me in business to get to 1 million
subscribers. It's pretty cool. But, like
subscribers actually don't matter. Like
ask any YouTuber and they'll tell you
that subscribers
subscribe count really doesn't matter.
It's about the engagement ratio. Like
the number of people who uh click on
every new announcement, cuz, you know,
who knows what the algorithm, whether or
not it feeds it to you, seems to be pot
luck, and whether or not people click
seems to be pot luck. Um, well, now if
you've got a click-baity thumbnail or
something, you might get some more
clicks, but yeah, it's a tough business
cuz everyone's in it now. When I started
this 17 years ago, back in 2009, I only
remember there being
Jerry Ellsworth and Mike from Mike's
Electric Stuff who had channels, but
they didn't have like a regular, I don't
think they had a regular segment.
Although, I didn't discover their
channels until after I had uh started
mine, but I was the first one to start
numbering, you know, number one, number
two, and then, um, yeah, make a regular
thing out of it, and then go full time
at this crazy business. God, I haven't
worked full time for over 15 years. Can
you believe it?
I can't.
Never going back to working for the man.
But, do I work for the man? Do I work
for Neal Mohan? Or, do I work for you
guys? Do I work for myself? I don't
know. It's YouTube. Uh.
So, that's it. It's a gold play button.
Cool bananas.
Thoughts and comments down below, as
always, you can check out the EEVblog
forum down below, and EEVblog.store,
which is what keeps me in business these
days, because the ad revenue is kind of
declining. It ain't just me, it's
everyone. It's a tough game.
Don't recommend it, kiddies.
Uh, no, it's better than working for the
man.
Catch you next time.
>> [music]